我们来到海边
Ok so we went to the beach
因为菲比找到一个
because Phoebe found out about this Iady
认识她父母的女人
who knew her parents,
然后我就不知道发生什么了
and I don't know what happened.
我是你的母亲
I'm your mother.
莫妮卡开玩笑说
Monica joked
她不会跟钱德勒这种人约会的
she wouldn't date chandler.
其实他一直很在意
And he couIdn't let her go
然后我也不知道发生什么了
I don't know what happened there either.
罗斯的新女友邦妮登场
Ross' new girlfriend shows up.
瑞秋说服她剃了个光头
RacheI convinced bonnie to shave her head.
然后瑞秋跟罗斯接吻了
then they kiss.
现在罗斯得在瑞秋跟光头女之间二选一
Now Ross has to choose racheI or the baId girl.
我还是不知道发生什么了
I don't know what happened there either.
等一下  我去找钱德勒来
You know what. HoId on. Iet me go get chander.
瑞秋在帮我擦药  我的头晒伤了
Rachel was just heping me. my head's sunburned.
-感激不尽  -您太客气了
-thanks a million. -you're wecome a million.
我先回房间了
Okay I'll be in our room.
太好了
Oh, my god!
我懂得
I know.
我得走了
I got to go.
我得跟邦妮分手了
I got to go break up with bonnie.
现在  在这儿吗
Here? now?
我又不能整完留在这里
Well yeah I can't stay here all night.
要是我回房间  她就会
and if l go in there, she'll want to...
想要嘿咻
...do stuff.
你就不能说你没心情
Can't you say you aren't in the mood?
她就喜欢那样
No, she likes that.
装睡也不管用
Faking sleep doesn't work.
我经常早上醒来发现她在
I can't tell you how many mornings I woke up with her...
-跟你说这个干嘛  -我不知道
-why am l telling you? -l don't know.
-也不是每天早上都要  -越描越黑
-not every morning-- -making it worse!
我猜想得到 你大概想知道前因后果
So I guess you'd like to know how it all happened.
我想 我大概想得明白
I-I mean I, well I think I can figure it out. I
我出生之后  大家就开始卯起来撒谎
guess y'know I was born, and everyone started lying their asses off!
不是那样的
No, it wasn't like that.
我不是说过  莉莉还有法兰克和我都很要好
Remember how l said lilly, frank and l were close?
我们非常要好
We were very close.
有多好
How close?
我们三个是一对
The three of us were kind of a couple.
我都不明白三个人也可以
I don't know how that would work.
我不是在问你
I'm not asking!
总之  我不知怎的怀孕了
Anyhow, somehow l got pregnant...
我那时
...and l was...
害怕极了  愚昧又自私
...scared. l was stupid and selfish....
那时我才18岁
I was 1 8 years old.
你还记得你的18岁
I mean, you remember what it's like to be eighteen years old?
记得 妈妈自杀了  爸爸逃走了
Yeah. Let's see, my had Mom killed herself, and my Dad had run off,
我跟一个叫山迪的人住在一起
I lived in a gremlin with a guy
他会跟他的手说话
who talked to his hand.
对不起  我以为他们是世上最好的父母
I'm sorry. l thought l'd left you with the best parents.
直到几年前我才听到他们的消息
I didn't hear about them till a few years ago.
当时你已经长大了
By then, you were already grown-up.
我不知道  既然你来了
I don't know You're here
我真的想多了解你
and l would really like to get to know you.
大家都想认识我
Well, everybody does.
我是很酷的人
I'm a really cool person.
你有29年的时间可以来找我
You had 29 years to find out,
但你连试都没试过
but you didn't even try.
你扔下我不管
Y'know what, you walked out on me,
现在我也要
and I'm just, I'm gonna do the same thing to you.
我再也不想见到你了
I don't ever want to see you again.
我的包在哪儿
Where's my purse?
讨厌  汽水没了
Shoot! we're out of soda.
-我去买点  -真的吗
-l'll get you some. -really?
才不  我又不是你男友
No, because l'm not your boyfriend.
菲比  怎样了
Hey, pheebs, how'd it go?
我妈的朋友菲比  其实是我的亲生母亲
My mom's friend, phoebe, is actually my birth mom.
我捡到一个干掉的海马
I found a dried-up seahorse.
什么意思
Sweety, what are you talking about?
我的新妈妈当年抛弃了我
My new mom, who's a big fat abandoner.
你不坐下来聊一聊
Don't you wanna stay here and talk about it?
我想自己静一静
I need to be alone.
莫妮卡
Monica
结束了
It's over.
很惨吗
Was it awful?
拖了很久
It was long.
我都不知道几点了
I didn't realize how late it was...
直到她头上出现5点钟的影子
...till l saw the five o'clock shadow on her head.
她不想留了  我叫车送她走了
Anyway She didn't want to stay. l called a cab. she just left.
我写了封信给你
I wrote you a letter.
谢谢
Oh, thank you!
我喜欢看信
I like mail.
我想了一些关于我们
It's just some things l've been thinking about. about us.
在我们考虑复合之前
Before we even think about the two of us getting back together...
我得知道你对这封信的看法
...l need to know how you feel about this stuff.
现在是早上5点半
it's 5:30 in the morning.
我最好赶快看完
So l'd better get cracking on this baby.
我等你  看完就上来
I'll be waiting for you. come up when you're done.
我得花上
I'll be up...
18页的时间
...in 18 pages.
双面的哟
Front and back.
太兴奋了
Very exciting!
你怎么没上来
What happened to you? why didn't you come up?
看完了
Done.
-你才刚看完  -我想看仔细点
-you just finished? -l wanted to be thorough.
显然  这对你我很重要
This is clearly very important to you. to us.
所以我想一字一句用心斟酌
And so I wanted to read every word carefully.
两边哟
Twice.
所以  行吗
Does it?
抱歉
I'm sorry?
好吗
Does it?
行吗  好吗
Does it? does it?
我想再瞄一眼
I wanted to give that whole
行吗的部分
''does it?'' partto think about i
什么意思  你说你看了两次
What are you talking about, Ross, you just said that you read it twice!
行不行一句话  如果你还要考虑
Look, y'know what, either it does or it doesn't, and if you have to even think about it
不  我不用考虑 不用
No, Rach, no. I don't, I don't, I don't have to think about it,
事实上
In fact...
我已经决定了  我要
...l've decided. l have decided...
这件事
...that it...
行
...does.
-你想好了吗  -当然啊
-are you sure? -sure, l'm sure!
如果发生核爆炸  我是唯一幸存的男人
There's a nuclear holocaust. l'm the last man on earth.
你会跟我约会吗
Would you go out with me?
我可有罐头食物哦
I've got canned goods.
你们来看
Hi guys Take a look at this!
看看我挖了个洞
Check this baby out! dug me a hole.
干得好啊
Excellent hole, joe.
不  我的洞
Oh, no! my hole!
我的脚
My foot!
怎么了
What is it?
我被水母咬了  痛死了
Jellyfish sting! lt hurts!
我扶你回去
Can we help you to the house?
有2里啊
It's two miles.
我挖洞挖的好累
And l'm tired from digging.
可恶的水母
Damn the jellyfish!
死水母
Damn all the jellyfish!
想想办法
We've got to do something!
只有一个办法
Well, there's really only one thing you can do.
什么办法
What?! What is it?!
在伤口上撒尿
You're gonna have to pee on it.
什么 好恶
What?!! Gross!!
别怪我  我是在探索频道上看到的
Don't blame me, I saw it on The Discovery Channel.
他没唬你  尿液里有氨之类的
Y'know what, he's right. There's something like uh,ammonia in that
可以止痛
...that kills the pain.
我不要  其实也没那么  痛
Well forget it! It doesn't hurt that baaad!!!!
你可以躲进我的洞里
If you want some privacy you can use my hole.
我准备好要走了
Well, I'm ready to get the hell out of here!
你们 真的
Oh. Are you? Are you?!!
太棒了
Ohh! That's so great!!
邦妮好可怜
Not for bonnie.
但恭喜你们了
But for you, yea!
-海边好玩吗  -不怎样  我不知道
-how was the beach? -nothing. l don't know.
-怎么了  -没事
-what happened? -nothing.
-我去洗澡  -我也是
-l'm going to shower. -me too.
加我一个
Me too.
我把袋子拿到车上
Okay, I'm gonna put this in the car.
我得去收东西
Ooh, I have to go pack.
-真的行吗  -当然
-and it really does? -lt does.
真的行啊
It really and truly does.
行你个头
It so does not!
她要我对我们的失和
She wants me to take responsibility
负起全部的责任
for everything that went wrong in our relationship.
她写了整整五页
I mean she goes on for five pages about,
说我如何不忠
about how I was unfaithful to her!
可我们当时分手了
We were on a break!!!!!
天哪 你再说一次  我就跟你分手
Oh my God! If you say that one more time,I'm gonna break up with you!
好吧  可分手
Fine! Fine!
不是我一个人的错   她写说
But this break-up was not all my fault, and she, she says here,
要是你负起全部的责任
If you accept full responsibility...
全部的  我就能再次信任你
Full responsibility! l can begin to trust you again.
你想你办得到吗  行吗
Does that seem like something you can do? does it?''
不行
No?
你得偿所愿 跟她复合了
Look, Ross, you have what you want, you're back with Rachel.
要是你现在提出来
If you bring this up now,
你会毁了你一生中最美好的事
you'll wreck the best thing that even happened to you.
我知道  你说得对
Yeah, I know. I mean, no,
我会就此打住
Yeah I guess I'll let it go.
但你们知道这件事很难忘记
But you-you understand how-how hard it is to forget about this.
当然很难
Sure, it's hard to forget!
但你不必拿出来谈
But that doesn't mean you have to talk about it!
这次度假有很多事
A lot of things happened on
都该从此绝口不提
that we should never, ever talk about.
在海边到底怎么了
What the hell happened on that beach?!
那是我们和大海的秘密  罗斯
It's between us and the sea, Ross!
乌苏拉
Hi, Ursula.
我知道  我们很久没联络了
Okay, well umm, I know that we haven't talked in a long time but umm
但我们的妈妈不是亲妈妈
okay, our Mom is not our birth Mom.
另一个女的才是
This-this other lady is our birth Mom.
对  住在莫陶克的那个
Right, okay, the one that lives in Montuak, umm-hmm.
你认识她
You know her?!
不认识  但妈的遗书里有提到
No, I umm, I read about her in Mom's suicide note.
妈有留遗书  你还有存着吗
There-there was a suicide note?! Well, do you still have it?
等一下
Hang on.
你居然没告诉我有遗书
I can't believe you didn't tell me there was a suicide note!
是啊  你最近怎样
Yeah. So how have you been doing?
我  闭嘴
I, umm, shut up!
别了  菲比与乌苏拉  我会想念你们
Good-bye Phoebe and Ursula. I'll miss you.
又  你们母亲住在莫陶克
P.S. Your Mom lives in Montauk
这是你刚才写的
You just wrote this!
差不多就是这个意思
Well, it's pretty much the gist.
只差那首诗 你读过那首诗
Well, except for the poem. You read the poem, right?
没有
Noooo!!
等一下
All right, hang on!
请把起司给我
Pass the cheese, please.
你连看都不敢看我 对吧
My God, you can't even look at me! Can you?
对
Nope.
是菲比  我们可以跟菲比说话
Hey! Phoebe! We can talk to Phoebe!!
我很沮丧  不想说话
No. I'm-I'm too depressed to talk.
我给你1千元开口费
I'll give you a thousand dollars to talk to us.
我们要不要
Hey, you guys! What do you,
每年都去海边玩
what do you think about making that beach trip an annual thing?
不要
No!!!
够了 到底出了什么事
All right, that's it, you guys! What happened out there?
什么  我们只是去散步  没什么
What? we took a walk. nothing happened.
我身上什么都没沾到
I can back with nothing all over me.
到底怎么了  乔伊
Come on! What happened? Joey?
好吧  我说
All right.
不行  我们发誓要死守秘密
No! Joey, we swore we'd never tell!
他们不会了解的
They'll never understand!
我们得说出来  我快被逼疯了
Well, we have to say something We have to get it out! It's eating me alive!!
-莫妮卡被水母咬到  -好吧
-Monica got stung by a jellyfish.. -all right!
我被咬到
I got stung.
咬得很严重
Stung bad.
站都站不直
I couldn't stand.
走也走不动
I couldn't walk.
我们离小屋2里远
We were two miles from the house.
孤单又害怕
Scared and alone.
我们还以为死定了
We didn't think we could make it.
我痛得要命
I was in too much pain.
我刚挖完洞又好累
And I was tired from digging the huge hole!
然后乔伊想起一件事
And then Joey remembered something.
是在探索频道上看到的
I'd seen this thing on The Discovery Channel...
慢着  我也看过
Wait a minute!
是探索频道没错  它说要是你被水母
On the discovery channel. about jellyfish and how if you--
你在自己身上撒尿
Ewwww!! You peed on yourself?!
你不能这么说 你不知道
You can't say that!! You-you don't know!!
我都快痛昏了
I mean I thought I was gonna pass out from the pain!
我试过  但没办法
Anyway I-I tried, but I-I couldn't..
但没办法弯成那样
...bend that way.
没错 我挺身而出
That's right I stepped up!
她是我的朋友 她需要帮助
She's my friend and she needed help!
如果有必要  我也会在你们身上撒尿
And if I had to, I'd pee on anyone of you!
只不过
Only...
我不能
...l couldn't.
我怯场了
I got the stage fright.
我很想帮忙 但压力太大了
I wanted to help, but there was too much pressure.
所以我找钱德勒
So-so I uh, I turned to Chandler.
乔伊一直对我大叫  快尿  快点尿
Joey kept screaming at me, ''do it now. do it. do it now!''
有时在深夜里 我还会听到那个叫声
Sometimes late at night I can still here the screaming.
那是我在隔壁吓你
That's 'cause sometimes I just do it through my wall to freak you out.
大家都回去算算房里的颜色
I invite all of you to count the colors in your bedroom.
你除外 给我走开
Except for you. you go away.
我马上就走
I'll go in a second.
我只想告诉你
I just want to tell you...
我每天都在后悔把你送人
that there hasn't been a day where I didn't regret giving you up.
好  再见
Okay, bye.
我还没说完
No, I'm not done.
我想让你明白
I-I-I just want you to know that I,
我之所以没找过你是因为
The reason l never looked you up was because...
我很怕你的反应
well I was afraid that you'd react,
会跟现在一样
just well like, the way, the way you're reacting right now,
我们就不能从现在开始
and can't we just, y'know, start from here?
不行
No.
对不起
Sorry.
最后一件事
But just one last thing.
你来找你的家人
Y'know you came looking for family.
我就是
I'm family
没别人
I'm it.
我说完了
Now l'm done.
我们又没什么损失
But, it's not like we're losing anything. You'know?
你说得对
Yeah, I guess you're right.
我们又不熟  也没什么共同点
It's not like we-we know each other or anything. Or that have anything in common.
我不晓得  也不见得
I don't know. lt's not like...
完全没有共同点
...we don't have anything in common.
像我喜欢披萨
I mean, l like pizza.
我也喜欢
I like pizza!
等等 我喜欢披头士
Wait, l like the beatles.
天哪 我也是
Oh my God, so do I!
等等 小狗狗可不可爱
Wait-wait-wait, wait! Puppies. Cute or ugly?
可爱死了
So cute!
看吧
You see?
但我还是很气你
But l'm still mad at you.
我知道
I know.
我也很气自己
I'm mad at me too.
你想吃东西吗  我有点饿
Well umm, do you wanna get something to eat? I'm kinda hungry.
我也是
Hey! Me too!
可以了啊  你吓到我了
All right, stop it. Now you're just doing it to freak me out.
我想你
I missed you.
我也想你
I missed you too.
我对那封信好紧张
I was so nervous about that letter.
但是你这么坦然认错
But the way you owned up to everything,
证明你真的成长不少
it just showed me how much you've grown. Y'know?
大概
I suppose.
你有 罗斯 你不该妄自菲薄
You have! Ross, you should give yourself credit.
我妈一直觉得我们无法复合
I mean my Mom never thought this would work out.
她说  出轨是不可原谅的
It was all,  Once a cheater, always a cheater.
真希望没有这4个月的空白
Ooh, I just wish we hadn't lost those four months,
但要是时间
but if time was what you
能让你看清楚一点
to gain a littles perspective...
我们当时分手了
We were on a break!!!!!!!
-咖啡吗  -好
-coffeehouse? -you bet.
这段感情  会破裂是两个人的错
And for the record, It took two people to break up this relationship.
对 你和影印店那个女的
Yeah! You and that girl from that copy place,
你昨天表明愿意负责
which yesterday you took full responsibility for!!
我不知道我负的是什么责
I didn't know what I was taking full responsibility for! Okay?
我没把信看完
Okay?! I didn't finish the whole letter!
我睡着了
I fell asleep!
你竟然睡着了
You fell asleep?!
当时是早上5点半
5:30 in the morning,
你一废话就写了十八页
And you had rambled on for 18 pages.
还是两面的
Front and back!!
还有  你得是指  你必须
By the way, y-o-u-apostrophe-r-e means ''you are.''
是指  你必须
Y-o-u-r means ''your.''
我居然会想
Y'know I can't believe I even thought
跟你复合  我们根本就完了
about getting back together again! We are so over!!
无所谓
Fine by me!!
你星期六晚上 跟莫妮卡玩拼字游戏时
Oh, oh, and hey-hey-hey, those little spelling tips will come
一定不会写错字
in handy when you're at home on Saturday nights playing Scrabble with Monica!!
对不起
Sorry!!
我只可怜你  会想我想到失眠
I just feel bad about all that sleep you're gonna miss wishing you were with me!
别怕我睡不着
Oh, no-no-no don't you worry about me falling asleep.
我还有你的信
I still have your letter!
顺便告诉你  这种事并不常见
And hey! Just so you know, it's not that common!
并非男人都会这样
It doesn't happen to every guy.
这是很严重的
And it is a big deal!
我就知道
I knew it!
我赢了
Gin.
我们在玩金罗美牌
We were playing gin?
男女朋友就会光着身体玩
Y'know if we were a couple, we could play this game naked.
-别再说了  -好吧
-would you stop? -okay. all right.
好吧
Okay. All right.
我觉得你很棒
I think you're great.
我觉得你人很好  很聪明
I think you're sweet and smart...
我爱你
...and l love you.
但你永远是在我身上撒尿的人
But you'll always be the guy who peed on me.